Andrew Ashland

Programmer/Web Developer

1424 Newman Ave. Lakewood OH, 44107

(216) 820 0074

https://ashlandportfolio.herokuapp.com

https://github.com/biochem6

SUMMARY

I am a software developer focused on web-development and building enterprise application software using visual studio and the .net framework. I am comfortable working in both front and back-end development. My previous experience as an EHS coordinator I led operational projects, designed and wrote protocols, conducted audits, held training classes, met and negotiated with vendors, and complied with state and federal regulations. As a supervisor I managed multiple departments and employees, solved technical, as well as departmental issues, ensured employee compliance with various regulatory bodies, and continuously worked to improve both the employees and departments that I managed. I am very confident I can quickly become a valuable asset to your company.

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS+

- Strong front and back-end development skills
- Strong understanding of object-oriented programming and SOLID design principles
- Knowledge of the software development lifecycle SDLC
- Prioritize responsibilities to meet strict deadlines
- Excellent problem solver and team player, I adapt and work well in any environment

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- HTMI 5
- CSS3
 - Responsive Design
 - Mobile First
 - CSS grid and Flexbox
 - Bootstrap
- JavaScript
 - o ECMAScript 6
 - jQuery
 - DOM Manipulation

- C#
- OOP
- LINQ
- WPF Applications
 - o MVVM Design Pattern
- ASP.NET Webpages
 - o MVC Design Pattern
 - URL Routing
 - Entity Framework
 - Code-First Migrations
- Net Framework
 - Visual Studio 2017
 - Nuget package Manager

- Version Control
 - o git and github
 - Azure DevOps
- SQL
 - CRUD Operations
 - MySql

EXPERIENCE

ATI Aviation Services, 12401 Taft Ave. Cleveland OH, 44108

EHS Coordinator, Plating and Lab Department Supervisor - March 2018 - February 2019

- Ensure the proper disposal of hazardous waste in compliance with state and federal regulations
- Perform safety audits of the facility, hold safety training courses, comply with OSHA regulations
- Troubleshoot plating line issues and make adjustments when necessary

Component Repair Technology, 8507 Tyler Blvd, Mentor, OH 44060

Lab Technician - October 2015 - December 2017

- Analytical testing of chemical tanks
- Prepared hazardous waste for disposal
- Responsible for making up new chemical tanks

EDUCATION

Kent State University, Kent OH - Bachelor of Science - Molecular Biology

Graduated May 2015